Andrew Blair Grimes

Austin, TX 78702 ♦ (512) 696-4184 ♦ drew@grimes-design.com

INDUSTRIAL DESIGNER

Web Developer / Product Development / Graphic Design / 3D Modeling

I am a self-motivated, talented, and quality-minded designer backed by Solidworks CSWP certification, with a B.F.A. in Industrial Design from CCAD, and 15 years of creative work experiences. I have a passion for creative design and craftsmanship. I am a hands-on designer from conceptualization to final product development, and extremely effective in both self-managed and team environments.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Github, Trained by Austin Coding Academy, 2016 Solidworks CSWP certified, SW Essentials & Advance Part Modeling, Trained by GoEngineer, 2012 PTC Pro/E Wildfire 4.0, Sheet metal & Solid Modeling, Trained by Impact System Engineering, 2004 B.F.A., Industrial Design, Columbus College of Art & Design (CCAD), Columbus, 2002

MANUFACTURING SKILLS

Sheet Metal Design / Sand & Permanent mold, Die-cast Casting / Plastic Part design / Injection molding / Vacuum Forming / Tooling Mold Design / CNC programming / Machined and Welded Part Design / Welding Processes MIG/TIG/Stick / Rapid Prototyping / Manufacturing & Assembly Drawing / Package Design / Product Installation and Assembly Instructions / FMEA / 6 Sigma / UL Standards / ANSI / OSHA / CE

COMPUTER SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite / Photoshop / Illustrator / Indesign / Dreamweaver / CSS3 / HTML5 / BootStrap 3 /cPanel / Github / Atom / Sublime Text 3 / Big Commerce / Constant Contact / Wordpress / Pro/E / Solidworks / AutoCAD / SketchUp / Keyshot / MS Office suite

WORK HISTORY

Grimes-Design. Freelance / Contract Designer. Austin, TX, Industrial / Graphic / Web / Design

2016-Current

ClimbTech. Fall Protection. Austin, TX, Industrial Designer

2012-2015

- Work directly with engineering and marketing on new and existing product.
 - Re-designed instruction manuals, labeling, packaging and marketing materials for new and existing products.
 - Photograph and edit photos of product for marketing materials and website use.
 - Work directly with new OEM and distributors re-branding our products and literature to suit their needs.
 - Assist engineering with 3d modeling (SolidWorks, KeyShot) for appearance models and graphics.
 - Testing failure mode of new and existing products for quality control and R&D.
 - Work in the machine shop to build test fixtures or working on small runs for production.
 - Assist production with manufacturing when need and help to resolve problems with current orders when they arise.

Bay 11 Studio. Austin, TX.

2009-2012

Owner / Designer

My company specializes in graphic design, branding, CNC Co2 laser cutting & etching, signage and custom printed apparel. I design, produce, and restore unique signage and murals. I help develop and create product for clients for both production and one off custom designs.

list of Past Clients Bay 11 Studio:

Stubb's BBO Leaders in Leather Clown Dog Bikes Darkeyes Clothing The Decoder Ring The Omelettry Hoek's Pizza Big Red Sun Hoboken Pie Melissa Borrell Design Habitat for Humanity Spider House Café Texas Coffee Traders Slow Food Austin Big Medium I Luv video Simmer Down Chill Out Pump Project

Big Medium, A Non-profit Based Organization for the visual arts

2010-2013

Volunteer / Designer

- Assisted and transformed building space into gallery space for the Texas Biennial, East Austin Studio Tour and West Austin Studio Tours.
- Assisted in coordination of promotion events and parties for Texas Biennial and East Austin Studio Tour.
- Assisted in design of signage and installed store front displays for West Austin Studio Tour.
- Art installation for Texas Biennial, East Austin Studio Tour.

Acuity Brands. Lighting. Austin, TX.

2004-2009

Design Engineer

- Designed products in Pro/E and maintained files with Windchill. Model rendering done with KeyShot for marketing.
- Worked in R&D roll on special project and new products for indoor and outdoor, LED, HID, and florescent lighting.
- Develop rapid prototyping department for engineers and designers.
- Assisted marking department with promotional materials and new product concepts.
- Worked directly with sale staff and clients for custom mounting or modifications for specific applications.
- Worked directly with manufacturing in house and internationally to resolve and streamline production and assemble products. Traveled yearly to Mexico to oversee and coordinate with the foundry.
- Sourced and worked directly with venders and suppliers
- Designed sheet metal parts, aluminum and iron casting, plastic part and die-casting.
- Laid out and illustrated installation and assembly instructions.
- Designed cardboard boxes and packaging for products.
- Sustained engineering for existing products

Louis Sign Builders, Inc. Austin, TX Graphic Designer

2003-2004

- Worked with clients designing custom signage and company logos and letterheads.
- Built signs for production work, including vinyl graphics channel letters and other types of sign fabrication.
- On sight installation of all types of signage, from window graphics to channel letters and other large signs.
- Apprentice electrician, responsible for wiring back lighted signs and other type of lighting applications.

Interests & Hobbies

Vintage car & motorcycle restoration / Bicycle riding / Kayaking / Photography / Sculpture / Building and fabrication / Landscaping / Traveling / Discovering new music / Programing

Online Portfolio: http://www.grimes-design.com/

^{*}I would be more than happy to provide references if need. My driver's license and passport are current and I am willing to travel as needed for projects.